(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-05T21:58:25.130725",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
君を泣かすから だから一緒には居れないな
Since I'll only make you cry, I can't stay together with you.
君を泣かすから 早く忘れて欲しいんだ
Since I'll make you cry, I want you to forget me soon.
人間だからね たまには違うものも食べたいね
We're human after all, sometimes I want something different to eat too.
君を泣かすから そう 君を泣かすから
Because I make you cry, yes, because I make you cry.
でも味気ないんだよね
But it's so dull, isn't it?
会いたいんだよね 君以外会いたくないんだよね
I want to see you, I don't want to see anyone else.
なんて勝手だね
How selfish of me.
大体曖昧なんだよね 愛の存在証明なんて
The proof of love's existence is mostly so vague.
君が教えてくれないか
Won't you teach me?
何十回の夜を過ごしたって 得られないような
Something you can't get even by spending dozens of nights together—
愛してるを並べてみて
Try lining up "I love you"s.
何十回の夜を過ごしたって 得られないような
Something you can't get even by spending dozens of nights together—
最高のフルコースを頂戴
Give me the ultimate full-course meal.
君を泣かすから きっと一生は無理だよね
Since I'll only make you cry, a lifetime together is surely impossible.
君を泣かすから 胸がとても痛くなんだ
Because I make you cry, my chest hurts so much.
人間だからね たまには分かり合えなくなって
We're human after all, sometimes we fail to understand each other.
君を泣かすから また君を泣かすから
Because I'll make you cry, I'll make you cry again.
でも自信がないんだよね
But I lack confidence, don't I?
Even though I lack confidence,
変わりたくないんだよね
and don't want to change,
君以外会いたくないんだよね なんて勝手だね
wanting to see no one but you... how selfish of me.
大体曖昧だったよね
It was mostly all vague,
愛の存在証明なんて
like proof of love's existence,
君がそこに居るのにね
even though you were right there.
何百回の夜を過ごしたって得られないような
Like something you could never get by spending hundreds of nights
愛してるを並べてみて
lining up "I love you"s,
何百回の夜を過ごしたって得られないような
like something you could never get by spending hundreds of nights,
最高のフルコースを頂戴
give me the ultimate full course meal.
離れないで傍に居てくれたのは 結局君一人だったよね
In the end, you were the only one who stayed by my side without leaving.
涙のスパイスは君の胸に残ってしまうだろうけど
Though the spice of tears will likely remain in your heart,
何千回の夜を過ごしたって得られないような
like something you could never get by spending thousands of nights
愛してるを並べるから
I'll line up "I love you"s,
何千回の夜を過ごしたって得られないような
like something you could never get by spending thousands of nights,
最高のフルコースを頂戴
give me the ultimate full course meal.
何万回の夜を過ごしたって忘れぬような
Like something you could never forget by spending tens of thousands of nights,
愛してるを並べるから
I'll line up "I love you"s,
何万回の夜を過ごしたって忘れぬような
like something you could never forget by spending tens of thousands of nights,
最高のフルコースを頂戴
give me the ultimate full course meal.
お疲れ！右手にはマイク、左手にはチーズ、あなたのハートをゼルゲス！ということでAZKiです！みんな！
Good work! Microphone in right hand, cheese in left hand, capturing your hearts—I'm AZKi! Everyone!
ああ、こおずきこおずき！え、本日は、
Ah, Cozki Cozki! Uh, today,
AZKi活動6周年記念ライブ「百花繚乱」へお越しいただきありがとうございます！
thank you so much for coming to AZKi's 6th Anniversary Live "Hyakkaryouran"!
このね、今日ライブのタイトル「百花繚乱」はですね、いろいろな花が咲き乱れることということで、
Today's live title, "Hyakkaryouran", means various flowers blooming in profusion,
本当に今日は色々なことを詰め込んで、想いや、内容モリモリでお届けしていきたいと思います！よろしくお願いします！
so today I want to deliver a packed show filled with various feelings and a wealth of content! Thank you very much!
ということで、1曲目は「晩餐歌」でした！どうだったかな？どうだった？どうだった？どうだった？
And with that, the first song was "Bansankou"! How was it? How was it? How was it? How was it?
はい、秋のね、こんな秋の夜に、なんかしみじみと聴きたくなるバラードからお届けいたしました！
Yes, in this autumn night, I delivered a ballad that makes you want to listen and reminisce!
そしてそして、冒頭でも説明しましたが、今日は活動6周年は…
And, as I explained at the beginning, today's 6th anniversary is...
わい わい わい わい！イェーイ！ということで、
Yay, yay, yay, yay! Yay! So,
活動当初は6年を迎えられるなんて本当にAZKi思っていませんでした。今日この日を迎えられることは、本当に本当に応援してしてくれるみんながいるからです。
At the start of my activities, I really never thought I'd reach 6 years. Being able to welcome this day is truly, truly because everyone who supports me is here.
え、本当に様々な分岐点を経て、このライブができることが本当に本当に嬉しいです！ありがとうございます！
Um, going through various turning points, I am truly, truly happy to be able to hold this live! Thank you very much!
体力戦の皆、ありがとう！
Everyone who gave their all, thank you!
はい、え、次は、え、本日のハッシュタグの紹介です。
Yes, um, next is the introduction of today's hashtag.
今日のハッシュタグは、こちら！え、AZKi新衣装3Dライブ！ということで、
Today's hashtag is right here! Uh, "AZKi New Outfit 3D Live"! So,
え？待って。新衣装3Dライブ？ってことは？
Eh? Wait. New outfit 3D live? That means?
はい。この後、後半に新衣装のお披露目あります！ね、もうこのね、今キービジュアルがね、ほら、後ろに見えていますけれども、これなのか？これなのか？
Yes. Afterward, in the second half, there's the unveiling of the new outfit! Right, you can see the key visual right behind me now—is it this? Or is it this?
どうなのか？ここまで言っといて違ったらどうしよう。ということで、新3D衣装もあります！お披露目もありますのでよろしくお願いします！
How will it be? What if I say all this and it's wrong? So, there is a new 3D outfit! There's an unveiling too, so please look forward to it!
お披露目のあとは写真撮影タイムもあるので、たくさんスクショして、たくさんポストしてくれると嬉しいです！
After the unveiling, there's also a photo-shooting time, so I'd be happy if you take lots of screenshots and post them a lot!
もちろんライブの感想などのポストも大体大歓迎
Of course, posts with your impressions of the live are also very welcome.
長めです！
It's quite long!
はい、今日のね、ライブは
Yes! Today's live concert,
前半は、活動6年で頑張ってきたあずきのご褒美的な感じで、
for the first half, as a reward for AZKi working hard over 6 years,
本当に本当にやりたいことを詰め込みました、欲張りセットな感じで（笑）。
I crammed in everything I really, really wanted to do—a greedy set, lol!
そして、後半はですね、今回ね、キービジュアルからも分かるかもしれませんが、ちょっと和風、和風なコンセプトでお届けしたいと思います。お楽しみに！
And for the second half, you might be able to tell from the key visual, but we'll be delivering it with a Japanese-traditional concept. Look forward to it!
この後はゲストが登場するのでお楽しみに！
Guests will be appearing after this, so look forward to it!
それでは、コラボパート、登場！
And now, the collab part, enter!
愛のネタバレ 別れっぽいな
Love spoilers, looks like a breakup.
人生のネタバレ 死ぬっぽいな
Life spoilers, looks like death.
なにそれ意味深で かっこいいじゃん…
What's with that deep and cool vibe...
それっぽい単語集で踊ってんだ 死け
Dancing with a vocabulary that sounds like it... Die!
とぅるとぅるとぅるふー っぽいじゃんぽいじゃん
Tu-lu-tu-lu-tu-ru-fu— So like it, so like it!
とぅるとぅるとぅるふー
Tu-lu-tu-lu-tu-ru-fu—
神っぽいな
So god-like.
もういいぜ もういいぜ
Enough's enough, enough's enough,
それもいいぜ 逆に興奮してきたなあ
that's fine too, I'm getting kind of excited.
おっきいね おっきいね 夢おっきいね おっきいね
So big, so big, such a big dream, so big!
景気いいけど 品性はTHE END
Business is booming, but class is THE END.
うええい うええい
Ueei! Ueei!
“Gott ist tot”
Gott ist tot
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 神っぽいな それ “My God”
So god-like, how cowardly. So god-like, "My God."
アイオウォンチュー ウォンチュー IQが下がっていく感じ
I want you, want you, feeling my IQ dropping.
邪心っぽいな それ 卑怯 邪心っぽいな それ
So girlish, how cowardly. So girlish, right?
アイハイチュウ ヘイチュウ 害虫はどっち
I-hi-chu, hei-chu, which one's the pest?
その髪型 その目 その口元 その香水 その服 そのメイク
That hairstyle, those eyes, that mouth, that perfume, that outfit, that makeup—
アレっぽいな それ 卑怯 アレっぽいな それ
So cliché, how cowardly. So cliché, right?
その名言 その意見 その批評 そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
That famous quote, that opinion, that criticism, that charisma, that gag, that sense—
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 神っぽいなぽいなぽい 憧れちゃうじゃん
So god-like, how cowardly. So god-like, making me admire it!
とぅるとぅるとぅるふー
Tu-lu-tu-lu-tu-ru-fu—
っぽいじゃん っぽいじゃん とぅるとぅるとぅるふー
So like it, so like it! Tu-lu-tu-lu-tu-ru-fu—
神っぽいな
So god-like.
メタ思考する 本質は悪意?
Is the essence of meta-thinking malice?
人を小馬鹿にしたような作為
An artifice that looks down on people.
無為に生き延びるのは難しい
Surviving idly is difficult.
権力に飲まれて 揺らぐ灯り
A flickering light swallowed by power.
神を否定し 神に成り代わり
Denying God and taking His place,
玉座で豹変する小物達
small fries transforming suddenly on the throne.
批判に見せかけ 自戒の祈り
Prayers of self-admonition disguised as criticism,
Do you know?
何言ってんの? それ ウザい
What are you talking about? So annoying.
何言ってんの? それ 意味がよくわかんないし
What are you talking about? I don't really get what it means,
眠っちゃうよ マジ
I'm gonna fall asleep, seriously.
飽きっぽいんだ オーケー みんな 飽きっぽいんだ オーケー
Everyone gets bored easily, okay? Everyone gets bored easily, okay?
踊れるやつ ちょうだい ちょうだい ビーム
Give me something danceable, give me, give me a beam!
きっしょいね きっしょいね それきっしょいね きっしょいね 逆にファンになってきたじゃん
So gross, so gross, that's so gross, so gross—wait, I've actually become a fan!
ちっちゃいね ちっちゃいね 器ちっちゃいね ちっちゃいね
So petty, so petty, such a small vessel, so petty!
天才ゆえ 孤独ですね かっけぇ…
Lonely because of genius, how cool...
“Gott ist tot”
Gott ist tot
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 神っぽいな それ
So god-like, how cowardly. So god-like, right?
超健康 健康 言い張って くたばっていく感じ
Insisting you're super healthy while collapsing.
やけっぽいな それ 卑怯 やけっぽいな それ “My God”
So desperate, how cowardly. So desperate, "My God."
もう哀愁 哀愁 エピゴーネンのヒール
Already sorrow, sorrow, the epigon's heel.
そのタイトル その絵 そのストーリー その音楽 その歌 そのメロディ
That title, that artwork, that story, that music, that song, that melody—
アレっぽいな それ 卑怯 アレっぽいな それ
So cliché, how cowardly. So cliché, right?
その名言 その意見 その批評 そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
That famous quote, that opinion, that criticism, that charisma, that gag, that sense—
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 神っぽいなぽいなぽい 憧れちゃうじゃん
So god-like, how cowardly. So god-like, making me admire it!
とぅるとぅるとぅるふー っぽいじゃん っぽいじゃん
Tu-lu-tu-lu-tu-ru-fu— So like it, so like it!
とぅるとぅるとぅるふー 神っぽいな
Tu-lu-tu-lu-tu-ru-fu— So god-like.
愛のネタバレ 別れっぽいな
Love spoilers, looks like a breakup.
人生のネタバレ 死ぬっぽいな
Life spoilers, looks like death.
すべて理解して 患った 無邪気に踊っていたかった人生
Understanding everything and falling ill, I just wanted to dance innocently through life.
生の本音はエグいから
Raw honesty is harsh,
ちゃんと火を通して食べてね
so cook it thoroughly before eating!
リップサービスはズルいから
Lip service is sneaky,
それも一筋縄じゃいらんない
so it's not going to be that simple.
みんな自分偽ってるかい？
Are you all faking who you are?
嘘の万国博覧会
An international expo of lies.
みんな自分偽ってるかい？
Are you all faking who you are?
嫌いだけど好き マスクしても美味しい
Even if I hate you, I like you, tasty even with a mask
着ぐるみを着てハグしてあげる
I'll wear a costume and give you a hug
泣かせないように 怒らせないように
So as not to make you cry or get angry,
ちょうどよく君と遊びたいのだ
I just want to play with you nicely.
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Neko kaburiina, Neko kaburiina!
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like you who are a bit timid.
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Neko kaburiina, Neko kaburiina!
取り繕ってるぼくが好き
I like myself putting up a front.
弱さを知ってる君が好きだよ
I love that you know my weaknesses.
「思う」と「言う」とでは大違い
"Thinking" and "saying" are totally different,
建前も用法と用量次第
even facades depend on proper use and dosage.
災難だけど「ハッピー」深刻でも「ヘイキ」
A disaster, but "happy," serious, but "fine,"
アベコベな夢を見せてあげる
I'll show you a topsy-turvy dream.
夜明けまで君とふざけ合うのだ
I want to fool around with you until dawn.
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Neko kaburiina, Neko kaburiina!
爪を丸めてる君が好き
I like you with your claws pulled in.
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Neko kaburiina, Neko kaburiina!
涙を見せないぼくが好き？
Do you like me who never shows tears?
弱さを知ってる君が好きだよ
I love that you know my weaknesses.
君はネコ ネコ ファスナー付きのネコ
You're a cat, a cat, a cat with a zipper.
君はヒト ヒト ファスナー付きのヒト
You're a human, a human, a human with a zipper.
あれはufo ufo ファスナー付きのufo
That's a UFO, a UFO, a UFO with a zipper.
君はネコ ネコ ファスナー付きのネコ
You're a cat, a cat, a cat with a zipper.
君はヒト ヒト ファスナー付きのヒト
You're a human, a human, a human with a zipper.
あれはufo ufo ファスナー付きのufo
That's a UFO, a UFO, a UFO with a zipper.
君は誰 誰 特別な人
Who are you, who are you? A special person!
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Neko kaburiina, Neko kaburiina!
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like you who are a bit timid.
君も僕も馴染めない世界で やっと見つけた居場所だから
In a world where neither of us fits in, it's our place.
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Neko kaburiina, Neko kaburiina!
取り繕ってるぼくが好き
I like myself putting up a front.
君も僕もとかしてる世界で 明日もまた会えたらいいな
I hope we can meet again tomorrow.
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Neko kaburiina, Neko kaburiina!
弱さを知ってる君が好きだよ
I love that you know my weaknesses.
らん だむ ぶ れい ん ！ わ おっ
Pekorandombrain! Wao!
ランダムレインボー 叫んじゃえわおっ
Random rainbow, shout it out, wao!
事件だ 毎日タイヘン
It's an incident, everyday is tough!
大成功のタネだ と笑え…泣いちゃうな笑え！
Smile, saying it's the seed of success... don't cry, smile!
ぺこらんだむるんるんらんだむ
Pekorandom runrun random,
ぺこらんだむぶしちゃいたまえ
Pekorandom, why don't you try it?
no , no 脳の指令無視か yes かうりゃー
No, no, ignoring brain commands, yes or uryaa!
no , no 脳の指令ランダムだ random!
No, no, brain commands are random, random!
no , no 脳の指令無視か yes かうりゃー
No, no, ignoring brain commands, yes or uryaa!
no , no 脳の指令ランダムだ random! 受け取り拒否れぬソング
Random! A song you can't refuse!
なんたいがいなテンション
What outrageous tension!
ぎゅんとプロペラまわれ
Spin the propeller tight!
どこへ向かうかは知らない 知りたくないんだ
Where we're heading, I don't know, don't want to know.
なんと世界はつながっちゃう
Suddenly the world connects!
ひょいと越えたら銀河系
Hop across and it's the galaxy!
誰に会いたいかって思うんだ
Who do I want to see, I wonder?
そんなのどうでもいいじゃんいいじゃん
That kind of thing doesn't matter at all!
退屈嫌いだったらこっち来れば？
If you hate boredom, why not come over here?
まずは一歩目からだ 千里はちょっとムリだ！
Start from step one, a thousand miles is too much!
やばい本音だ！ まっけっまっけまっけまっけ
That's my true feelings! Losing, losing!
思わずできちゃったよ ～
Accidentally made it happen ~
ぺこらんだむぶれいんっ！わおっ
Pekorandombrain! Wao!
びっくりだわおっ
Surprise, wao!
生きてりゃ毎日タイヘン
Being alive is tough every day,
大問題のあとには楽しいことあるから
because good things come after big problems.
ぺこらんだむぶれいんっ！わおっ
Pekorandombrain! Wao!
叫んじゃえわおっ
Shout it out, wao!
事件だ 毎日タイヘン
It's an incident, everyday is tough!
大成功のタネだ と笑え…泣いちゃうな笑え！
Smile, saying it's the seed of success... don't cry, smile!
ぺこらんだむるんるんらんだむ
Pekorandom runrun random,
ぺこらんだむぶしちゃいたまえ
Pekorandom, why don't you try it?
no , no 脳の指令無視か yes かうりゃー
No, no, ignoring brain commands, yes or uryaa!
no , no 脳の指令ランダムだ random!
No, no, brain commands are random, random!
no , no 脳の指令無視か yes かうりゃー
No, no, ignoring brain commands, yes or uryaa!
no , no 脳の指令ランダムだ random! 受け取り拒否れぬソング
Random! A song you can't refuse!
どんな空でも here we go くるっと機体がまわる
No matter the sky, here we go, spinning around!
どっちが地面とか知らない 知りたくないんだ
Which way is the ground? I don't know, don't care.
どうかしてて褒め言葉？ どうもならないよりましさ
Is that a compliment? Better than nothing!
誰かに会いたいって言ってよね！ 嬉しいからね やっほーやっほー
Say you want to see someone! I'm happy, yaho!
だあもならないよりました
Better than nothing at all!
誰か会いたいって
Someone wanted to meet me,
言ってたよね 嬉しいからね
so they said, right? I'm so happy!
ヤッホ ヤッホ
Yoo-hoo, yoo-hoo!
冒険選ぶなら
If you're choosing adventure,
こっち来れば？
why not come this way?
コラボだもん
Because it's a collab!
まずは一歩目からだ
First, from the very first step!
千里はちょっとムリだろ
A thousand miles might be a bit much!
やばい本音だ
That's a dangerous true feeling!
待って待って待って 思わずできちゃったよ
Wait, wait, wait! It happened before I knew it.
ペコランダムぜいんは
Pekorandambrain!
脳内からはめちゃくちゃやってみるか
Let's mess things up completely in our brains!
大混乱も大好き
I love total chaos too!
楽しいなら大好き
If it's fun, I love it even more!
ペコランダムぜいんは歌っちゃえは
Pekorandambrain, just sing it out!
まだまだやっちゃうかな
Shall we keep on doing it?
大旋風吹き荒れろ
Let a great whirlwind rage on!
笑え明日も笑え
Smile, smile tomorrow too!
ペコランタールンルンラッタ
Pekoran ta runrun ratta!
ペコランダッシュジョイタマイ
Pekoran dash joy tamai!
脳がなんか伝えがかる
My brain is trying to convey something:
変われ変われ世界中
"Change, change, all around the world!"
ジャンプじゃえ変えるために
Jump! To change things,
皆々聞こえるかい 聞こえるかい？
can everyone, everyone hear me? Can you hear me?
ランダムぜいんはびっくりだわ
Random-brain is a surprise!
生きてりゃ毎日大変
Living means everyday is tough,
大問題の後には楽しいことあるから
but after big problems, there are fun things waiting!
ランダムぜいんは叫んじゃえは
Random-brain, just scream it out!
事件だ毎日大変 大成功のタネだと
Everyday is a crisis, but it's the seed of great success—
笑えないじゃうな笑え
Don't cry, smile instead!
ペコランタールンルンラッタ
Pekoran ta runrun ratta!
ペコランダッシュジョイタマイ
Pekoran dash joy tamai!
ペコランタールンルンラッタ
Pekoran ta runrun ratta!
ペコランダブノノノノエーーイ！
Pekoran da vonononono-ei!
はい、ということで、ゲストのふたりのオリ曲を中心に3曲お届けいたしました。
Yes, so we delivered three songs centered around the original songs of our two guests!
そしてね、ブライト衣装に着替えてまいりました。がーん！ブライト衣装と、
And you know, I changed into my bright outfit! Ta-da! My bright outfit, and...
ということで、お届けした曲のね、ちょっとね、感想なんかも言っていこうかなと思います。
with that, I'd like to share some of my thoughts on the songs we delivered.
まず、かみっぽいな。今回ね、どうしてもこの3人で歌ってみりたくて、え、おかゆんとぺこちゃんをお呼びいたしました。
First, "Kamippoi na". I really wanted the three of us to sing this together, so I invited Okayu and Peko-chan.
なんか、なかなか、なんかダークなAZKiこういうライブの曲あんまりやってないなと思って、
I felt like I don't usually do such dark songs for live shows,
ちょっといつもよりダークな感じで、もうすごくすごく歌い割りも歌詞のパート分けもめちゃくちゃ悩みながら、このぺこちゃんに歌ってもらうにはどこがいいかなとか、おかゆんに歌ってもらうのはどこがいいかなとかすごく夜な夜な考えて、
so with a darker vibe than usual, I struggled so much over the lyric parts division—wondering where would be best for Peko-chan or Okayu to sing—thinking about it late into the night.
え、このかみっぽいなをお届けいたしました。どうだった？
And so we delivered "Kamippoi na". How was it?
もうめちゃくちゃ歌うの難しかったから、すごくすごくダンスもダンスみんなでね頑張りました。どうだったかな？
It was super hard to sing, so we all worked really hard on the dance too. How did you like it?
はい、そして、次はフカカユンのオリ曲、猫カブリーナ。
Yes, and next was Okayu's original song, "Neko Kaburīna".
もうこれはずっとずっとAZKiがおかゆんと一緒に歌って踊りたかった曲でして、もう振り付けもかわいいじゃん、この。
This is a song AZKi has always, always wanted to sing and dance to with Okayu. The choreography is so cute, right?
もうめちゃくちゃかわいくて、おかゆん一緒に歌ってくれる？ってお願いしたところ、一緒に歌ってくれました。
It's so cute, and when I asked Okayu, "Will you sing it with me?", she happily agreed.
そして、なんと、え、おかニャン、おかニャンも登場してくれました。AZKiがどうしてもどうしてものおかニャン、おかニャンにずっとおかニャンの良さについてえと語っていたんですけれども、
And what's more, Oka-nyan even made an appearance! I had been talking endlessly about how great Oka-nyan is,
今回まあおじして、おかニャンにも登場していただけました。ということで、AZKiのすごいあのやりたいことをねこのパートでちょっと詰め込んでみました。
and this time, we finally had Oka-nyan make an appearance too. So I packed all the things AZKi really wanted to do into this part!
おかニャンと一緒にお踊れたし、めちゃくちゃ幸せな6周年を迎えておりますということで、猫カブリーナでございました。
I got to dance with Oka-nyan too, and I'm celebrating a super happy 6th anniversary! So that was "Neko Kaburīna".
そして、次はずんだむぶれいん。もうこれはねぺこちゃんの曲の中でAZKiもすごいすごいすごいずっとずっと大好きで、いつかぺこちゃんと一緒に歌いたい歌いたい歌いたいと
And next was "Pekorandambrain". This is one of Peko-chan's songs that AZKi has loved so, so, so much for the longest time, always dreaming of singing it together with Peko-chan.
思っていたので、え今回ぺこちゃんの曲をぺこちゃんと一緒に歌えて幸せでございます。
So I am so happy to be able to sing Peko-chan's song together with Peko-chan today!
...なことしたかったので、どうだったで
...what it would be like, so how was it?
しょうか！
Showcase!
いや、めちゃくちゃ今日はね、百花
Yeah, today's 100-flower...
繚乱ということで、いろんな花が咲き乱れていきます！という事で、
...Ryoran, so flowers are all over the place!
え、次らは
Next up is...
皆さん、お待たせいたしました！新曲を
...everyone, thanks for waiting!
お披露目して行きたいと思います！え、曲中に、なんと大、大、大、大、大、大変、新
We'll unveil the new song, so look forward to it!
しちゃいますので、お楽しみにー！
...changes happen, so please look forward to it!
それでは、次の曲
Then, the next song...
どうぞ！
...please!
大胆不敵にハイカラ革命
With a bold and daring, high-collar revolution,
磊々落々反戦国家
a chaotic, rebellious state of tumult and fall.
日の丸印の二輪車転がし悪霊退散ＩＣＢＭ
A two-wheeled cart marked with the rising sun, expelling evil spirits: ICBM.
環状線を走り抜けて
Running through the loop line,
東奔西走なんのその
running east and west, what is that all about?
少年少女戦国無双浮世の随に
A peerless warring era for boys and girls, lost in the floating world.
千本桜夜に紛れ
Thousands of cherry blossoms dissolving into the night,
君ノ声モ届カナイヨ
not even your voice will reach.
此処は宴鋼の檻
This place is a banquet inside a steel jail cell,
その断頭台で見下ろして
look down from that guillotine.
三千世界常世之闇嘆ク唄モ聴コエナイヨ
Three thousand worlds, the darkness of eternity; not even a lamenting song can be heard.
青藍の空遥か彼方その光線銃で打ち抜いて
Shoot right through the azure sky far away with that ray gun!
百戦錬磨の見た目は将校
Hundreds of battles give the appearance of an officer,
いったりきたりのおいらん道中
going back and forth on a courtesan promenade.
あいつもしこいもみんなで集まれ
Those guys and these guys, everyone gather around,
聖者の行進わんっつーさんし
it's a saintly march, one, two, three, four!
禅定門を潜り抜けて
Slipped past the dhyana gate,
安楽浄土厄払い
cleansing evils to reach the Pure Land of ultimate bliss.
きっと最後は大団円
Surely the end is a grand finale,
拍手の合間に
amidst the sound of applause.
千本桜夜に紛れ君ノ声モ届カナイヨ
Thousands of cherry blossoms dissolving into the night, not even your voice will reach.
此処は宴鋼の檻その断頭台で見下ろして
This place is a banquet inside a steel jail cell, look down from that guillotine.
三千世界常世之闇嘆ク唄モ聴コエナイヨ
Three thousand worlds, the darkness of eternity; not even a lamenting song can be heard.
希望の丘遥か彼方その閃光弾を打ち上げろ
Shoot up your flash grenades toward the hill of hope far away!
環状線を走り抜けて東奔西走なんのその
Running through the loop line, running east and west, what is that all about?
少年少女戦国無双浮世の随に
A peerless warring era for boys and girls, lost in the floating world.
千本桜夜に紛れ君ノ声モ届カナイヨ
Thousands of cherry blossoms dissolving into the night, not even your voice will reach.
此処は宴鋼の檻その断頭台を飛び降りて
This place is a banquet inside a steel jail cell, leap off from that guillotine.
千本桜夜に紛れ君が歌い僕は踊る
Thousands of cherry blossoms dissolving into the night, you will sing and I will dance.
此処は宴鋼の檻さあ光線銃を撃ちまくれ
This place is a banquet inside a steel jail cell, shoot wildly and ceaselessly with your ray gun!
はい、ということで、お送りしたのは千本桜でしたー！
Yes, so the song we just played was "Senbonzakura"!
はい！じゃーん！なんと、こちらが新衣装、3D新衣装でございまーす！
Yes! Ta-da! Behold, this is our new outfit, our new 3D outfit!
なんと、まさなお正月衣装となっておりますー！
It has become a New Year's outfit!
で、先ほど千本桜の曲に合わせて、桜で衣装チェンジしました！
And earlier, matching the song Senbonzakura, I changed my outfit to cherry blossoms!
で、こちらは今年ね、お正月に公開している衣装で、
This is an outfit that was revealed this year for New Year's,
3Dのお披露目は今日が初めてになりますー！いかがでしょう？すごい可愛いでしょう？
and today is the very first time revealing it in 3D! What do you think? Isn't it super cute?
はい。そして、お披露目はなんと、これだけじゃないんです！
Yes. And that's not all for the reveals!
もう、なんだろうな、なんだろうな、ということで呼び込みたいと思います。
Let's bring someone out. Wonder what it could be, wonder what it could be... Let's call them in!
開拓者ー！
Kaitakusha!
なー、ということで、なんとなんとなんと、なんとえー開拓者がお正月衣装ー！
Ta-da! So, lo and behold, the pioneer got a New Year's outfit too!
かーい！なんとね、このAZKiの今回の新衣装に合わせて開拓者もおめかししておもらいましたー！
Look at that! Matching AZKi's new outfit this time, the pioneer also got dressed up!
えーとね、なんかね、いろんなね、開拓者動きができるって聞いてるので披露してもらおうかな？
Umm, I heard the pioneer can do various movements now, so I'd love to have them show us!
じゃあ、AZKiのこと応援して！
So, go on and cheer for AZKi!
ペンライト、ペンライト持ってくれてる。
They're holding penlights, penlights!
そして、じゃあAZKiのね、AZKiといえば開拓者、開拓者のマーク押しまーす！
And then, AZKi's... speaking of AZKi, it's the pioneer! Let's press the pioneer mark!
あ、ちゃんと出るね！ハンマーとつるはし持ってますね。
Oh, it appears properly! They're holding a hammer and a pickaxe.
可愛いじゃないの！
Aren't they adorable!
そして、あ、そうだな、開拓者くん、やっぱさ、秋だよね。
And, oh right, Pioneer-kun, after all, it's autumn, right?
AZKiと一緒に紅葉を、ミニ紅葉。
Let's go see autumn leaves together with AZKi, mini autumn leaves.
笑え。
Laugh.
笑ってくれた、ありがとうありがとう！
They laughed for me, thank you, thank you!
えー、ということで、あ、すごい喜んでるね、喜んでるね！このちょっとお正月衣装になった開拓者でございます。髪飾りと、締めの後。
Uh, so, ah, they look super happy, they're so happy! This is the pioneer in the New Year's outfit. With hair ornaments and after tying...
ね、すごい、あの正月感満載なんですよ！
You know, it's overflowing with New Year vibes!
ちょっとね、開拓者の、え、お正月開拓者と一緒に写真を撮りたいと思います！
I'd like to take a picture with the New Year's pioneer!
えーと、じゃあここら辺かな？ここがな？はい、皆スクショタイムだよー！
Umm, then around here? Here? Yes, everyone, it's screenshot time!
あ、笑っててもいいけど、じゃれ、えっと、開拓者マーク！あーありがとう！あ、この開拓者もいいですね。
Ah, you can laugh, but play, um, pioneer mark! Ah, thanks! Ah, this pioneer is good too.
じゃああとペンライトペンライト！ペンライトの開拓者！
Then also penlight penlight! The penlight pioneer!
はい、みんな撮れた？お正月のAZKiと開拓者でございます！ということで、
Yes, did everyone take it? It's AZKi and the pioneer for New Year's! And with that,
じゃ、ステージの中央に戻りまして、
let's return to the center of the stage,
ではね、ここからもスクショタイムということで、いくつかAZKiもポーズをとるので、みんなスクショしていってね！
and now, from here on, it's also screenshot time, so AZKi will strike a few poses, everyone go ahead and take screenshots!
え、何がいいかな？ま、今日、今回の着物じゃなんか、こうやってね、こう袖をね、こうやっていっぱい広げていたので、どうでしょう？どうでしょう？可愛い衣装。
Um, what would be good? Well, today, with this kimono, spreading out the sleeves like this... how is it? How is it? Cute outfit.
そして、で、ちょっと振り、振り向きとかでするか。
And let's try turning around or something.
と、この、この角度どうですか？どうでしょうか？
And, how is this angle? What do you think?
あの、普通に可愛くピースしよう。ピース！
Um, let's just do a cute peace sign. Peace!
どっかな？え、撮れてる？
How is it? Um, did you get it?
あーありがとう！そして、おなこ、ちょっと手を広げたりしたりして、一緒に、お正月、な感じ。
Ah, thanks! And, like this, spreading my hands out a bit, together, giving a New Year's vibe.
はい、そして、あ、ちょっと細かいところみんなに見 てほしいなと思うので、
Yes, and, ah, I want everyone to see the fine details up close, so
ぜひこのカメラ、カメラさん、カメラマンさん、このね、足の方から見てください。このね、可愛いブーツと、この袴の可愛い柄と、
please, camera, camera person, camera-san, look from the foot area. This cute boot, and the cute pattern of the hakama,
あとね、この袖のピンクの可愛い柄になってます！後ろはこんな感じ。はい！
and also this pink cute pattern on the sleeves! The back looks like this. Yes!
そしてね、ベレー帽も可愛いでしょう、髪飾りも。可愛くお仕立ていただきましたー！わーい！
And you know, the beret is cute too, and the hair ornaments. It was tailored so cutely for us! Yay!
え、そしてね、まだちょっと違うね、サブンとかもあるんだけど、
Um, and also, there are still some different versions,
この後、面ででアマスことなくお見せいたしますので、気になった方はぜひこの後の面前のライブもよろしくお願いしますー！
and I'll be showing them all without holding back in the upcoming stream, so if you're curious, please check out the stream after this as well!
はい！ということで、え、ここからはこの今日ねお披露目した新衣装に合わせて、和風コンセプトで和テイストな曲をお届けしていきたいと思いますー！
Yes! With that, from here on, matching the new outfit we revealed today, we'd like to deliver songs with a Japanese style and concept!
この後はちょっと曲に合わせて 衣装もちょっとずつ何かか 変化していったりするので
After this, in accordance with the song, my outfit will change a little bit too...
お楽しみにしてください。
so please look forward to it!
それでは次の曲へどうぞ！
Now then, please enjoy the next song!
引き裂いた 闇が吠え 震える帝都に
When the howling darkness is rent asunder and the capital trembles,
愛の歌高らかに 踊り出る戦士たち
We soldiers leap out, making the air ring with a love song.
心まで 鋼鉄に 武装する乙女
We are maidens armed with steel down to our hearts,
悪を蹴散らして 正義をしめすのだ
Scattering the forces of evil, we will show the way to justice.
走れ 光速の帝国華撃団
Run, fast-as-light Imperial Floral Assault Troop!
唸れ 衝撃の帝国華撃団
Roar, electrifying Imperial Floral Assault Troop!
帝国華撃団
Imperial Floral Assault Troop!
街の灯が 消え果てて 怯える帝都に
When the city lights have gone out and the capital is afraid,
虹の色 染め上げて 踊り出る戦士たち
We soldiers leap out dyed in rainbow colors.
暁に 劇情を 照らし出す乙女
We are maidens who light up the dawn with our passion.
悪を滅ぼして 正義をしめすのだ
Wiping out the forces of evil, we will show the way to justice.
走れ 光速の帝国華撃団
Run, fast-as-light Imperial Floral Assault Troop!
唸れ 衝撃の帝国華撃団
Roar, electrifying Imperial Floral Assault Troop!
帝国華撃団
Imperial Floral Assault Troop!
走れ 光速の帝国華撃団
Run, fast-as-light Imperial Floral Assault Troop!
唸れ 衝撃の帝国華撃団
Roar, electrifying Imperial Floral Assault Troop!
帝国華撃団
Imperial Floral Assault Troop!
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きが綺麗
Childhood dreams are unfading, beautiful scribbles...
思うまま描き滑らせて 描く未来へとつながる
sweeping across the page as we please, connecting to the future we draw.
澄み渡る空 果てしないほど青く
The clear sky is infinitely blue,
無邪気な 心に充たされ魅かれてく
Filled and charmed by an innocent heart.
やがて 自由に飛びまわれる羽を手に入れて
Eventually, gaining wings to fly freely,
無垢な瞳は求めてく 空の向こうへ行きたいな
My pure eyes seek to go beyond the sky.
止め処ない願いから 一つだけ叶うのなら
If one of my endless wishes could be granted,
誰にも譲りたくはない 夢を掴みたいと思うよ
I don't want to yield it to anyone; I want to grasp my dream.
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
Childhood dreams are unfading scribbles,
いつまでも描き続けられた 描く未来へとつながる
That can be drawn forever, connecting to the future we envision.
息呼、空は少しずつ白く
Ah, the sky is turning slightly white,
冷たい風も通り抜ける
and a cold wind blows right through.
昨夜であんなに騒いでたのも 嘘みたいなほど静かな朝
Even though we were partying hard last night, it's a morning as quiet as a lie.
uh 正しいことが何か 分からなくなってくる時間帯
uh, at times when you lose sight of what's right,
気持ちに素直になれるなら もうそれがきっと正解
if you can be true to your feelings, that's sure to be right.
君の近くにいるときと 寝ているときが幸せ
Being near you, or when you're sleeping, is pure bliss.
そっか難しいこと考えなくていいんだ
Ah, I don't need to overthink complicated things.
(ワッショイ！)
(Wasshoi!)
そんなことも知らずに 君は見てるあっちこっちどっち?
Without knowing any of that, you're looking this way and that.
夢の中ぐらいは もう少しこっち見てくれていてもいいでしょ
At least in dreams, could you look this way a bit more?
目が合って fu fu
Our eyes meet, fu fu,
触れて fu fu
touching, fu fu,
感じて fu fu
feeling, fu fu,
心が高鳴っていく
my heart beats faster.
さあ一人で fu fu
Now, alone, fu fu,
二人で fu fu
together, fu fu,
重ねて fu fu
intertwining, fu fu,
そのまま溶け合えたらタッタラ fu
melting into one just like this, tattala fu.
息呼、まどろむ雲は青く
Ah, the slumbering clouds are blue,
物寂しく風に揺れる
swaying lonely in the wind.
昨夜であんなにうるさかったのも 忘れるほど穏やかな朝
A morning calm enough to forget how noisy it was last night.
自分以外の子と話してるだけで 何だか気になる
Just talking to someone else makes me feel a bit uneasy.
やさしい言葉一つかけられるだけで すぐその気になる
Just one kind word is enough to make me fall for you.
「今何を考えてる?」とか 「誰を思ってる?」とか
Like "What are you thinking now?" or "Who are you thinking of?"
もうそんなことばかりで 思考も止まってさ
My thoughts stop with just things like that.
(ワッショイ！)
(Wasshoi!)
そんなことも知らずに 君はいつでもどこ吹く風
Without knowing any of that, you're always carefree.
夢の中ぐらいは もう少し近付いてても怒らないでよ?
At least in dreams, don't get mad if I get a bit closer, okay?
手を取って fu fu
Taking your hand, fu fu,
見つめて fu fu
gazing, fu fu,
笑って fu fu
smiling, fu fu,
あとはもうお気に召すまま
leave the rest as you please.
さあ右から fu fu
Now from the right, fu fu,
左から fu fu
from the left, fu fu,
前方から fu fu
from ahead, fu fu,
これが夢じゃなかったらタッタラ fu
if this wasn't a dream, tattala fu.
目が合って fu fu
Our eyes meet, fu fu,
触れて fu fu
touching, fu fu,
感じて fu fu
feeling, fu fu,
心が高鳴っていく
my heart beats faster.
さあ一人で fu fu
Now, alone, fu fu,
二人で fu fu
together, fu fu,
重ねて fu fu
intertwining, fu fu,
そのまま溶け合えたら
melting into one just like this...
さあ手を取って fu fu
Now taking your hand, fu fu,
見つめて fu fu
gazing, fu fu,
笑って fu fu
smiling, fu fu,
あとはもうお気に召すまま
leave the rest as you please.
さあ右から fu fu
Now from the right, fu fu,
左から fu fu
from the left, fu fu,
前方から fu fu
from ahead, fu fu,
これが夢じゃなかったらタッタラ fu
if this wasn't a dream, tattala fu.
せ〜の！ いち・に・さん・はい！
Ready, one, two, three, go!
ほい！
Hoi!
いよーーーっ、ぽん！
Yo----! Bon!
これよりご覧いただきますのは カブキ者たちの栄枯盛衰
What you are about to witness is the rise and fall of kabuki performers.
時代は常に日進月歩 聞いてってよ老若男女
Times are always changing, listen up, old and young, men and women.
一見は勧善懲悪 悪者どもを一刀両断
At a glance, rewarding good and punishing evil, cutting down villains in one stroke.
「でもホントにそれだけで楽しいの?」 もうなんだって紆余曲折
"But is it really that simple and fun?" Already full of twists and turns.
どこからともなく現れて すぐどこかへ行っちゃって神出鬼没
Appearing out of nowhere and vanishing just as quickly, elusive as gods and ghosts.
チャンスを待ったら一日千秋 追いかければ東奔西走
Waiting for a chance feels like a thousand autumns, chasing after it takes us far and wide.
時代は常に千変万化 人の心は複雑怪奇
Times are always changing in a thousand ways, the human heart is complex and mysterious.
「でも本気でそんなこと言ってんの?」 もうどうにも満身創痍
"But are you really serious about that?" Already battered and bruised all over.
息呼、巡り巡って夜の街 キミは合図出し踊り出す
Ah, wandering round and round the night town, you give the signal and start to dance.
はぁ?
Huh?
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ!
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華用に花弁 散らすように 髪も振り乱して
Like scattering flower petals brilliantly, letting your hair fly wildly.
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と この宴は続く
Day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, day after tomorrow, this banquet goes on.
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ! 今宵は雪月花
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart! Tonight is Setsugetsuka.
この世に平安訪れるの? のべ幕無し丁丁発止
Can peace ever visit this world? A continuous, fierce clash.
兵ども千客万来 ひしめき合う群雄割拠
Soldiers coming by the thousands, warlords vying for supremacy.
伸びるか反るか一攫千金 気付いたら絶体絶命
Making it big or losing it all, before you know it, you're in a desperate plight.
「でも本音のところ、どうなってんの?」 もうまったく奇想天外
"But what's the real truth behind it all?" Completely out of this world.
息呼、辿り辿って夜の街 迷い一つなく踊り出す
Ah, wandering through the night town, you start dancing without a single hesitation.
花で一つ、鳥で二つ 手打ち鳴らす
One for flowers, two for birds, clapping our hands.
風で三つ、息呼、月出て四つ 鳴らす鳴らす……
Three for wind, ah, four for the moon coming out, ringing and ringing...
今は 回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ!
Now spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華用に花弁 散らすように 髪も振り乱して
Like scattering flower petals brilliantly, letting your hair fly wildly.
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と この宴は続く
Day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, day after tomorrow, this banquet goes on.
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ! 今宵は雪月花
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart! Tonight is Setsugetsuka.
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like scattering flower petals brilliantly,
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin around, spin around, spin around!
髪も振り乱して
Disheveling your hair as well,
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と
The day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, the day after tomorrow,
この宴は続く
This banquet continues.
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ！
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart!
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is snow, moon, and flowers.
花で一つ、鳥で二つ
One with flowers, two with birds,
手打ち鳴らす
Clapping our hands in rhythm,
風で三つ、嗚呼、月出て四つ
Three with the wind, ah, four with the moon rising,
鳴らす鳴らす…
Playing on, playing on...
花で一つ、鳥で二つ
One with flowers, two with birds,
手打ち鳴らす
Clapping our hands in rhythm,
風で三つ、嗚呼、月出て四つ
Three with the wind, ah, four with the moon rising,
鳴らす鳴らす…
Playing on, playing on...
今は
Now...
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin around, spin around, spin around!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like scattering flower petals brilliantly,
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin around, spin around, spin around!
髪も振り乱して
Disheveling your hair as well,
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と
The day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, the day after tomorrow,
この宴は続く
This banquet continues.
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ！
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart!
今宵は何曜日か？
What day of the week is it tonight?
水木金？
Wednesday, Thursday, Friday?
土日月か？
Saturday, Sunday, Monday?
はい、ということで、3曲お送りいたしましたー！
Yes, with that, we performed 3 songs!
え、まずは劇帝国華撃団！
Um, first was Geki Teikoku Kagekidan!
ということテナで、やっぱ和っぽいなんか曲ないかなと思って
Thinking there must be some Japanese-style songs out there,
色々探して、あ、この曲歌いたいなと思って
I searched around and thought, "Ah, I want to sing this song,"
今日はこの衣装で歌わせていただきましたー！どうだったかな？
so today I sang it in this outfit! How was it?
なかなかね、こういう演出とかもできないので、今日はいろんな演出をして、みております
Since we can't usually do this kind of staging, today we're trying out various effects.
え、次は、え、無双歌をゲスト、ふうちゃんと一緒に歌いましたー！
Next, we sang "Musouka" with our guest, Fubu-chan!
無双歌、ふうちゃんと、ふうちゃんと一緒にライブしたいなってのもあったので、
I really wanted to do a live performance with Fubu-chan,
今回ね、ふうちゃんをお誘いして、大好きな無双歌という曲を歌いましたー！
so I invited her this time and we sang my beloved song "Musouka"!
そう、ふうちゃんもね、一緒に歌ってくれる、踊ってくれるということで、狐の、そう、お面なんかもね使ったりして
Right, Fubu-chan also sang and danced along, so we even used fox masks and such.
歌わせていただきました。どうだったかな？結構こだわりのお面外しで、
How was it? We worked hard on taking off those particular masks!
え、次は、え、回レ！雪月花。こちらは、え、船長にも来ていただき、
Next, "Maware! Setsugetsuka". For this one, Senchou also joined us,
ふうちゃんと、え、マリン船長と一緒に、お送りしましたー！この、回レ雪月花は、え、2年前、2022年に、
along with Fubu-chan and Marine-senchou! This "Maware Setsugetsuka", um, 2 years ago in 2022,
えっと、船長とふうちゃんと一緒にね、歌ってみたを出してまして
we released a cover version together with Senchou and Fubu-chan,
たくさんたくさん再生していただいてありがとうございます。このね、この輪のコンセプトライブで絶対やりたいなと
and thank you so much for all the views. I really wanted to do it at this ring-concept live,
思っていたので、このライブで披露することができて嬉しい限りです。めちゃんこね、あの、歌詞とか演出とかこだわって作りました。ありがとう！
so I'm beyond happy to unveil it here. We put so much care into the lyrics and staging. Thank you!
はい、ということで、次がラストの曲になりますー！ええ、今来たばっかりー！
Yes, with that, the next is the last song! "Eh, I just got here!"
をやって、ライブですから。え、この後、え、22時15分から、メンバー限定でアンコールライブがありまーす！
Well, since it's a live show. Um, after this at 22:15, there's a members-only encore live!
ぜひぜひ、このライブいいなって思ってくれたらメンバーシップ入っていただけるととっても嬉しいです。メンバーシップのアンコールライブでは引き続き、新曲では、テイストの曲を歌っていきます。
If you liked this live, I'd be super happy if you joined the membership. In the membership encore, we'll continue singing new-tasted songs.
今までの雰囲気とちょっと違うね、曲をセレクトしたので、ぜひぜひそちらもお楽しみにー！ということで、次がラストの曲ということなんですが、
We selected songs with a slightly different vibe from usual, so please look forward to that! With that, the next is the last song,
本当に改めて、活動6周年続けてこれたのは開拓者のみんなの応援のおかげです。
but truly once again, continuing for 6 years is thanks to everyone's support.
本当に本当に開拓者のみんなのパワーをめちゃくちゃいただいた、
I truly, truly received so much power from all the pioneers,
本当そんな年だったなって思います。
I feel like it really was that kind of year.
これからもたくさんみんなのこと、
Moving forward, for everyone,
みんなに楽しんでもらえるような
so that you can all enjoy yourselves—
配信だったり歌だったりを頑張っていきたいと思います。
I'll do my best with streams and singing!
みんなが元気になって、元気になって、
I hope everyone stays full of energy,
そして、癒し、癒しをもたらえられる存在に
and that I can be a presence that brings you healing—
なりたいなって、今後もそうなりたいなって思っているので、
I want to be that kind of existence, and I hope to continue being so.
これからも応援よろしくお願いします！
So I look forward to your continued support!
はい！
Yes!
それでは本当に本当に今日最後の曲です！
Now then, this is truly, truly the final song of today!
聴いてください！
Please listen to it!
寄り添うふたりに君がオーバーラップ
You overlap with the two of us walking close together,
色なき風に想い馳せて
sending my thoughts on the colorless wind.
触れた手のぬくもり今も
The warmth of the touch of our hands is still...
Stop 時間を止めて
Stop, make time stand still.
そういつの日だって
Yes, no matter what day it is,
君の言葉忘れないの
I will never forget your words.
会いたい時に会えない
When I want to see you, I can't.
切なくて もどかしくても
Even if it's painful and frustrating,
から紅に染まる渡月橋
Togetsukyo Bridge dyed in crimson,
導かれる日願って
praying for the day we are guided together.
川の流れに祈りを込めて
Putting my prayers into the river's flow,
I've been thinking about you
いつも心君のそば
My heart is always by your side.
いにしえの景色変わりなく
The ancient scenery remains unchanged,
今この瞳に移し出す
and now I reflect it in these eyes.
彩りゆく季節越えて
Crossing the changing seasons,
Stock 覚えていますか？
Stock, do you remember?
ねえいつになったら
Hey, when will the time come
また巡り会えるのかな
that we can meet again?
会いたい時に会えない
When I want to see you, I can't.
この胸を焦がすの
It scorches this heart of mine.
から紅に水くくるとき
When the crimson dyes the water,
君との想いつなげて
connecting my feelings with yours,
川の流れに祈りを込めて
putting my prayers into the river's flow,
I've been thinking about you
いつも君を探してる
I am always searching for you.
君となら不安さえ
With you, even anxiety
どんな時も消えていくよ
fades away at any time.
いつになったら優しく
When will the time come
抱きしめられるのかな
that I can be held gently?
から紅の紅葉達さえ
Even the crimson autumn leaves
熱い想いを告げては
confess their passionate feelings,
ゆらり揺れて歌っています
swaying gently as they sing.
I've been thinking about you
いつもいつも君想う
Always, always thinking of you.
AZKi活動6周年記念ライブ「百花繚乱」をご視聴いただきありがとうございました！
Thank you for watching AZKi's 6th Anniversary Live "Hyakka Ryouran"!
いろんな花が咲き乱れていましたでしょうか？
Did various flowers bloom in colorful splendor?
と、いうことで、最後にお知らせを3つします！
And with that, I have three announcements at the end!
え、1つ目はアンコールライブについてです。
Um, the first is about the encore live.
このあと22時15分からメンバー限定でアンコールライブを行います！
Afterwards, at 22:15, we'll hold a members-only encore live!
ライブだけじゃなくて衣装の詳細も紹介しますのでお楽しみに、よろしくお願いします！
I'll also introduce the details of the outfit, so please look forward to it!
そして2つ目は、こちら！
And the second one is right here!
グッズがでます！活動6周年記念グッズフルセットはこんな感じです！
Merchandise is out! The 6th Anniversary full merch set looks like this!
今回のグッズコンセプトは「和風でお出かけ」です！
The concept for this merchandise is "going out in Japanese style"!
1つずつ見ていきましょう！
Let's take a look at them one by one!
まずは、こちら！
First is this one!
卓上屏風！デスクや棚などに立てて飾れる和風イラストグッズ。
Desktop Folding Screen! Displayable on desks or shelves with Japanese illustrations.
雨の日に和服でお出かけしているキービジュアルを屏風にしてみました！
I turned the key visual of going out in a kimono on a rainy day into a folding screen!
イラストデータはHitenさん！幻想的な雰囲気のある感じに仕上げていただきました。
Illustrated by Hiten-san! They finished it with a fantastic, atmospheric feel.
次は、こちら！
Next is this one!
つながる3連アクリルキーホルダー！それぞれ1つのパーツだけでもチャームとして使えます。
Connecting 3-link Acrylic Keychain! Each individual part can be used as a charm.
順番を変えてもよし、別々で使ってもよし。
You can change the order or use them separately.
イラストはぜんちゃさんに描いていただきました！
The illustration was drawn by Zencha-san!
次は、こちら！
Next is this one!
開拓安全お守り！手のひらサイズのお守りです。
Pioneering Safety Amulet! A palm-sized amulet.
開拓安全の意味は、開拓者の安全を祈ることといろんな開拓、新しい分野だったり領域や新路を切り拓くという開拓の応援になったらいいなという気持ちを込めて作りました！
It's made to pray for pioneers' safety and support opening up new fields and paths!
次は、こちら！
Next is this one!
一緒に開拓！AZKiぬいぐるみパペット！帽子をかぶった外ロケお出かけスタイルのパペットです。男性の手のひらが入るくらいのサイズ感を目指しました。
Pioneer Together! AZKi Plushie Puppet! Designed for outdoor outings wearing a hat, sized for a man's palm.
イベントとかいろんなお出かけに連れていってくれたら嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you took it with you to events and outings!
ラストは、こちら！ボイスがでます！
Last is this! Voice packs are available!
内容は「雨の日に和服、お正月衣装の私と君が相合傘をしながらお散歩する」シチュエーションASMRボイスとなっております。雨音が聞こえる癒やし系ASMRボイスを目指しました。
It's a situation ASMR voice walking in kimono sharing an umbrella on a rainy day, aiming for a healing ASMR sound.
そして今回もあります！フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And we also have this! The full set purchase bonus is here!
ポストカード！キービジュアルとは違い笑顔のAZKiのポストカードです。
A postcard! Unlike the key visual, this postcard features a smiling AZKi.
通常版は箔押しですが、数量限定で直筆サインもあります！頑張って書きます！
The regular version has foil stamping, but there are also hand-signed ones in limited quantities!
直筆サイン入りが欲しい方は早めにご購入ください。よろしくお願いします！
If you want one with a hand signature, please purchase early. Thank you!
さらに今回は特典ボイスも付きます！通常販売のボイスの少し後のシチュエーションASMRボイスです。
Furthermore, a bonus voice is included! It's a situation ASMR voice right after the regular one.
内容は散歩していたら雨が強く降ってきたため家に帰ることにしたふたりのやりとりです。
It depicts the two deciding to go home because rain started falling heavily during their walk.
通常販売ボイス、特典ボイスは別々でも楽しめますが特典ボイスはより距離の近いふたりきり感を意識した内容になっています。傘は1つしかないからね、雨が強く降ったら濡れないようにみたいな感じです！
Both can be enjoyed separately, but the bonus voice focuses on the feeling of just the two of you being close.
そして、お知らせの3つ目、こちらをご覧ください！
And for the third announcement, please take a look at this!
月影揺れる 夜の小道
Moonlit flickering night path,
ヒラリ舞い散る 花の香り
the scent of gently scattering flowers.
カラカラと鳴る 風鈴の音
The clinking sound of wind chimes,
淡い夢が そっと囁く
a faint dream whispers softly.
影絵の中で踊る影
Shadows dancing within shadow pictures,
ゆらゆら揺れる 灯りの下
under the swaying, flickering lights.
彩り豊かな 夕焼け空
A vibrantly colored sunset sky,
キラリと光る 星の砂
and sparkling star sand.
過ぎゆく季節、音もなく
Passing seasons, without a sound,
心の奥に響く声
a voice echoing deep in the heart.
カゲロウの調べに乗せて
Carried on the melody of a heat haze,
君との記憶消えないように
so the memories with you will never fade.
結び合う手が伝うぬくもり
The warmth conveyed by our intertwined hands,
この瞬間を永久に刻む
etching this moment into eternity.
ひらひらと舞う、夜風に乗せ
Fluttering and dancing upon the night breeze,
共々に歩んだ日々を感じて
feeling the days we walked together.
未来を描く君と二人で
Drawing a future, just the two of us,
今宵もまた光の中へ
tonight once more into the light.
ということで、
With that said,
AZKiの新曲「カゲロウノ調」11月16日(土)配信リリース決定！
AZKi's new single "Kagerou no Shirabe" releases digitally on Saturday, Nov 16!
このあと11月16日(土)0時より各配信サービスにて配信開始！
Streaming starts right after at midnight on Saturday, November 16th!
さらに11月16日(土)21時からYouTubeプレミア公開！
Plus, the music video YouTube premiere starts Saturday, November 16 at 9 PM!
待機所はこの放送後、枠立てします。
We'll set up the waiting room right after this broadcast.
お楽しみに。さらに12月にも新曲あるかも。
Look forward to it! And maybe a new song in December too.
ぜひこちらも お楽しみに！以上、お知らせでした。
Please look forward to that as well! That's all for the announcements.
それではアンコールライブでお会いしましょう！今日はありがとうございました。バイバイ！
So let's meet again at the encore live! Thank you so much today. Bye-bye!